[
  {
    "id": 3501,
    "question": "escuches",
    "questionDetails": "Quiero que me hables o que escuches.",
    "answer": "listen",
    "answerDetails": "I want you to talk or listen."
  },
  {
    "id": 3502,
    "question": "disposición",
    "questionDetails": "Si no estás de acuerdo con esta disposición, no firmes el contrato.",
    "answer": "provision, disposal, disposition",
    "answerDetails": "If you don’t agree with this provision, you shouldn’t sign the contract."
  },
  {
    "id": 3503,
    "question": "servido",
    "questionDetails": "Lo he servido a usted por muchos años.",
    "answer": "served, availed, manned",
    "answerDetails": "I have served you for many years now."
  },
  {
    "id": 3504,
    "question": "alcance",
    "questionDetails": "Ampliamos el alcance de nuestra investigación.",
    "answer": "scope, reach",
    "answerDetails": "We widened the scope of our investigation."
  },
  {
    "id": 3505,
    "question": "suyos",
    "questionDetails": "Y, a cambio, los suyos también sean míos.",
    "answer": "yours",
    "answerDetails": "And in turn, that yours be mine too."
  },
  {
    "id": 3506,
    "question": "llegues",
    "questionDetails": "No llegues muy tarde.",
    "answer": "be",
    "answerDetails": "Try not to be too late."
  },
  {
    "id": 3507,
    "question": "misa",
    "questionDetails": "Todos los domingos, mi abuela va a la iglesia a escuchar misa.",
    "answer": "mass",
    "answerDetails": "Every Sunday, my grandmother goes to church to attend mass."
  },
  {
    "id": 3508,
    "question": "atiende",
    "questionDetails": "Atiende la puerta, como si todo estuviera bien.",
    "answer": "attends, caters, serves",
    "answerDetails": "Attends the door, as if everything was okay."
  },
  {
    "id": 3509,
    "question": "aceptado",
    "questionDetails": "Quiero ser aceptado en la mejor universidad del País.",
    "answer": "accepted",
    "answerDetails": "I want to be accepted at the country’s best university."
  },
  {
    "id": 3510,
    "question": "cojo",
    "questionDetails": "A pesar de su pierna cojo, huyó.",
    "answer": "lame",
    "answerDetails": "Despite his lame leg, he fled."
  },
  {
    "id": 3511,
    "question": "prepara",
    "questionDetails": "Un oficial listo se prepara para una campaña larga.",
    "answer": "prepares, readies, prep",
    "answerDetails": "A smart officer prepares for a long campaign."
  },
  {
    "id": 3512,
    "question": "velocidad",
    "questionDetails": "Brian recibió una bici de 7 velocidades en Navidad.",
    "answer": "speed",
    "answerDetails": "Brian got a 7-speed bike for Christmas."
  },
  {
    "id": 3513,
    "question": "dedica",
    "questionDetails": "Más dedica a su trabajo que a mi.",
    "answer": "dedicated, devoted, engaged",
    "answerDetails": "More dedicated to his job than me."
  },
  {
    "id": 3514,
    "question": "domicilio",
    "questionDetails": "¿Cuál es su domicilio, señor?",
    "answer": "address, domicile, abode",
    "answerDetails": "What is your address, sir?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3515,
    "question": "bolsas",
    "questionDetails": "Esta crema es excelente para camuflar las bolsas bajo los ojos.",
    "answer": "bags",
    "answerDetails": "This cream is great for disguising undereye bags."
  },
  {
    "id": 3516,
    "question": "aventura",
    "questionDetails": "¡ Nuestro viaje de safari en África realmente fue una aventura!.",
    "answer": "adventure, affair, fling",
    "answerDetails": "Our African Safari Trip was a real adventure!."
  },
  {
    "id": 3517,
    "question": "comes",
    "questionDetails": "Eso significa que comes tu propia comida.",
    "answer": "eat",
    "answerDetails": "That means you eat your own food."
  },
  {
    "id": 3518,
    "question": "miente",
    "questionDetails": "Sólo conozco el ruido que hace cuando miente.",
    "answer": "lies",
    "answerDetails": "I just know the sound it makes when it lies."
  },
  {
    "id": 3519,
    "question": "volvería",
    "questionDetails": "Lo volvería a hacer por ti.",
    "answer": "would",
    "answerDetails": "I would do it again for you."
  },
  {
    "id": 3520,
    "question": "pensamiento",
    "questionDetails": "El pensamiento sobre los beneficios del bilingüismo ha evolucionado mucho en los últimos años.",
    "answer": "thinking",
    "answerDetails": "Thinking on the benefits of bilingualism has evolved greatly in recent years."
  },
  {
    "id": 3521,
    "question": "papito",
    "questionDetails": "Debes buscar a mi papito.",
    "answer": "daddy",
    "answerDetails": "You must be looking for my daddy."
  },
  {
    "id": 3522,
    "question": "billete",
    "questionDetails": "Llevaba $100 encima en billetes de uno.",
    "answer": "bill, fare",
    "answerDetails": "He was carrying $100 all in $1 bills."
  },
  {
    "id": 3523,
    "question": "operativo",
    "questionDetails": "El transmisor está operativo.",
    "answer": "operative",
    "answerDetails": "The transmitter is operative."
  },
  {
    "id": 3524,
    "question": "escúcheme",
    "questionDetails": "Escúcheme usted a mí.",
    "answer": "listen",
    "answerDetails": "You listen to me."
  },
  {
    "id": 3525,
    "question": "imagínese",
    "questionDetails": "Imagínese si usted quería poner el jarabe en el agua.",
    "answer": "imagine",
    "answerDetails": "Imagine if you wanted to put syrup in water."
  },
  {
    "id": 3526,
    "question": "frontera",
    "questionDetails": "Laurie se hizo astronauta para tener una carrera en las fronteras del conocimiento humano.",
    "answer": "frontier, boundary",
    "answerDetails": "Laurie became an astronaut so she could have a career at the frontiers of human knowledge."
  },
  {
    "id": 3527,
    "question": "criminal",
    "questionDetails": "Nadie nace siendo un criminal.",
    "answer": "criminal, criminally, felon",
    "answerDetails": "One is not born a criminal."
  },
  {
    "id": 3528,
    "question": "maten",
    "questionDetails": "Tengo que estar allí cuando maten a ese hombre.",
    "answer": "kill, slay, whacked",
    "answerDetails": "I have to be there when they kill this man."
  },
  {
    "id": 3529,
    "question": "traidor",
    "questionDetails": "Esa mujer traidora se me fue y me dejó con el corazón roto.",
    "answer": "treacherous",
    "answerDetails": "That treacherous woman ran away and left me with a broken heart."
  },
  {
    "id": 3530,
    "question": "preocupen",
    "answer": "worry"
  },
  {
    "id": 3531,
    "question": "intereses",
    "questionDetails": "Pablo tiene intereses en varias inmobilarias en la China.",
    "answer": "interests",
    "answerDetails": "Pablo has interests in various construction companies in China."
  },
  {
    "id": 3532,
    "question": "sexual",
    "questionDetails": "La mejor experiencia sexual de mi vida.",
    "answer": "sexual, sexually, sex",
    "answerDetails": "Best sexual experience of my life."
  },
  {
    "id": 3533,
    "question": "regalito",
    "questionDetails": "Ha dicho que tenía un regalito para ti.",
    "answer": "gift",
    "answerDetails": "He said something about a gift for you."
  },
  {
    "id": 3534,
    "question": "evidencia",
    "questionDetails": "Los detectives no encontraron evidencia de que se tratara de un asesinato.",
    "answer": "evidence, proof",
    "answerDetails": "The detectives found no evidence that it was a murder."
  },
  {
    "id": 3535,
    "question": "conveniente",
    "questionDetails": "El sitio tendría que ser conveniente para Londres.",
    "answer": "convenient, suitable, appropriate",
    "answerDetails": "The site would have to be convenient for London."
  },
  {
    "id": 3536,
    "question": "hablen",
    "questionDetails": "Hablen con amigos, compañeros, el repartidor de pizza.",
    "answer": "talk, speak",
    "answerDetails": "Talk to friends, classmates, pizza delivery guy."
  },
  {
    "id": 3537,
    "question": "trató",
    "questionDetails": "Un panorama trató de componer dos piezas de fotografías.",
    "answer": "tried, treated, attempted",
    "answerDetails": "A panorama tried to compose two pieces of photographs."
  },
  {
    "id": 3538,
    "question": "huellas",
    "questionDetails": "Estos son dos juegos nuevos de huellas.",
    "answer": "footprints, prints, fingerprints",
    "answerDetails": "These are two new sets of footprints."
  },
  {
    "id": 3539,
    "question": "levante",
    "answer": "east"
  },
  {
    "id": 3540,
    "question": "bote",
    "questionDetails": "Remaron el bote hacia la orilla, rezando por su supervivencia.",
    "answer": "boat, dinghy, jar",
    "answerDetails": "They rowed the boat toward shore, praying they would survive."
  },
  {
    "id": 3541,
    "question": "hazte",
    "questionDetails": "Hazte fanático del hockey.",
    "answer": "become",
    "answerDetails": "Become a hockey fan."
  },
  {
    "id": 3542,
    "question": "pagarle",
    "questionDetails": "No tengo dinero para pagarle a nadie.",
    "answer": "pay, repay",
    "answerDetails": "I have no money to pay any of you."
  },
  {
    "id": 3543,
    "question": "mírate",
    "questionDetails": "Mírame a mí, y mírate a ti.",
    "answer": "look",
    "answerDetails": "Look at me, and look at you."
  },
  {
    "id": 3544,
    "question": "pidas",
    "answer": "Ask"
  },
  {
    "id": 3545,
    "question": "explique",
    "answer": "Explain"
  },
  {
    "id": 3546,
    "question": "piedras",
    "questionDetails": "Estaban en las piedras.",
    "answer": "stones, rocks, pebbles",
    "answerDetails": "You were at the stones."
  },
  {
    "id": 3547,
    "question": "prefiere",
    "questionDetails": "Su nombre es Micaela, pero prefiere llamarse Mick.",
    "answer": "she prefers",
    "answerDetails": "Her name is Micaela, but she prefers to be called Mick."
  },
  {
    "id": 3548,
    "question": "merecen",
    "questionDetails": "Realmente no merecen manejar la tienda.",
    "answer": "deserve, deserving, merited",
    "answerDetails": "You really don’t deserve to run the store."
  },
  {
    "id": 3549,
    "question": "cuadra",
    "questionDetails": "Buscamos alrededor de la cuadra.",
    "answer": "block",
    "answerDetails": "Looked around the block."
  },
  {
    "id": 3550,
    "question": "arrepiento",
    "questionDetails": "No me arrepiento de nada .",
    "answer": "regret, repent",
    "answerDetails": "I regret for nothing."
  },
  {
    "id": 3551,
    "question": "marcar",
    "questionDetails": "Cuelga el auricular y vuelva a marcar.",
    "answer": "dial, flag",
    "answerDetails": "Hang up and dial again."
  },
  {
    "id": 3552,
    "question": "vendió",
    "questionDetails": "Glenn se va a comprar un coche nuevo. Vendió el viejo la semana pasada.",
    "answer": "he sold",
    "answerDetails": "Glenn is going to buy a new car. He sold the old one last week."
  },
  {
    "id": 3553,
    "question": "rumbo",
    "questionDetails": "El gobierno tuvo que cambiar el rumbo de su política de austeridad.",
    "answer": "course, direction, bearing",
    "answerDetails": "The government was forced to change course on its austerity policy."
  },
  {
    "id": 3554,
    "question": "asumir",
    "questionDetails": "Él comenzó a asumir en sus ojos un aspecto romántico.",
    "answer": "assume",
    "answerDetails": "He began to assume in their eyes a romantic aspect."
  },
  {
    "id": 3555,
    "question": "bonitos",
    "questionDetails": "También sus gatos son muy bonitos.",
    "answer": "beautiful, pretty, cute",
    "answerDetails": "His cats are beautiful too."
  },
  {
    "id": 3556,
    "question": "preocupados",
    "questionDetails": "Sus familiares están preocupados.",
    "answer": "worried, concerned, apprehensive",
    "answerDetails": "Your relatives are worried."
  },
  {
    "id": 3557,
    "question": "circo",
    "questionDetails": "El circo viaja de ciudad en Ciudad para montar su espectáculo.",
    "answer": "circus, cirque",
    "answerDetails": "The circus travels from city to city to put on their performance."
  },
  {
    "id": 3558,
    "question": "ciertas",
    "questionDetails": "Hay ciertas cosas que jamás sabremos.",
    "answer": "certain, true",
    "answerDetails": "There are certain things we shall never know."
  },
  {
    "id": 3559,
    "question": "revisando",
    "questionDetails": "Pongo mi navaja, revisando la graduación.",
    "answer": "reviewing, checking, rechecking",
    "answerDetails": "I put my knife, reviewing graduation."
  },
  {
    "id": 3560,
    "question": "descubrió",
    "questionDetails": "Descubrió lo que había hecho Marco y lo dejó.",
    "answer": "she found out",
    "answerDetails": "She found out what Marco had done and left him."
  },
  {
    "id": 3561,
    "question": "grano",
    "questionDetails": "Si el azúcar hace el grano para arriba, agregue más agua.",
    "answer": "grain, corn, seed",
    "answerDetails": "If the sugar does grain up, add more water."
  },
  {
    "id": 3562,
    "question": "mandas",
    "questionDetails": "Cuando llegues a la base, me los mandas.",
    "answer": "send",
    "answerDetails": "When you get backto the base, send it back."
  },
  {
    "id": 3563,
    "question": "enterrar",
    "questionDetails": "Vine ante ustedes para enterrar al hombre.",
    "answer": "bury",
    "answerDetails": "I come before you now to bury the man."
  },
  {
    "id": 3564,
    "question": "dirás",
    "questionDetails": "Promete que no lo dirás.",
    "answer": "tell",
    "answerDetails": "Please just promise you won’t tell."
  },
  {
    "id": 3565,
    "question": "valen",
    "questionDetails": "Diez autos no valen la pena el esfuerzo.",
    "answer": "worth",
    "answerDetails": "Ten cars is hardly worth the effort."
  },
  {
    "id": 3566,
    "question": "directa",
    "questionDetails": "Puede que no sea capaz de comunicación directa.",
    "answer": "direct",
    "answerDetails": "It may not be capable of direct communication."
  },
  {
    "id": 3567,
    "question": "piensen",
    "questionDetails": "Les pedimos que lo piensen.",
    "answer": "think",
    "answerDetails": "Asked them that they think it."
  },
  {
    "id": 3568,
    "question": "contaron",
    "questionDetails": "Le contaron a su mamá sobre la nueva principal en la escuela.",
    "answer": "they told",
    "answerDetails": "They told their mother about the new principal at the school."
  },
  {
    "id": 3569,
    "question": "supieras",
    "questionDetails": "Suenas como si supieras algo de esto.",
    "answer": "know",
    "answerDetails": "You sound like you know something about it."
  },
  {
    "id": 3570,
    "question": "vendido",
    "questionDetails": "Más de la mitad de los apartamentos del edificio nuevo ya están vendidos.",
    "answer": "sold",
    "answerDetails": "More than half of the apartments in the new building are already sold."
  },
  {
    "id": 3571,
    "question": "abandonado",
    "questionDetails": "Un baile salvaje y abandonado.",
    "answer": "abandoned, derelict",
    "answerDetails": "A wild, abandoned dance."
  },
  {
    "id": 3572,
    "question": "sufrimiento",
    "questionDetails": "Poca gente ha padecido tanto sufrimiento como él.",
    "answer": "suffering, distress, misery",
    "answerDetails": "Few people have experienced such suffering as he has."
  },
  {
    "id": 3573,
    "question": "podremos",
    "questionDetails": "Creo que podremos hacerlo.",
    "answer": "can",
    "answerDetails": "I think we can handle that."
  },
  {
    "id": 3574,
    "question": "jugamos",
    "questionDetails": "Ayer, jugamos fútbol en la escuela.",
    "answer": "we played",
    "answerDetails": "Yesterday, we played soccer at school."
  },
  {
    "id": 3575,
    "question": "fotografía",
    "questionDetails": "Entiendo que te interesa la fotografía.",
    "answer": "photography",
    "answerDetails": "I understand you have an interest in photography."
  },
  {
    "id": 3576,
    "question": "entras",
    "questionDetails": "Abandona toda esperanza, tu que entras aquí.",
    "answer": "enter",
    "answerDetails": "Abandon all hope, ye who enter here."
  },
  {
    "id": 3577,
    "question": "presentado",
    "questionDetails": "Ese asunto será presentado ante el comité de disciplina.",
    "answer": "presented, submitted, filed",
    "answerDetails": "This matter will be presented to the disciplinary committee."
  },
  {
    "id": 3578,
    "question": "alarma",
    "questionDetails": "Señal de alarma.",
    "answer": "alarm",
    "answerDetails": "Alarm signal."
  },
  {
    "id": 3579,
    "question": "muestras",
    "questionDetails": "Aquí tiene las muestras.",
    "answer": "samples, signs, specimens",
    "answerDetails": "Here it has the samples."
  },
  {
    "id": 3580,
    "question": "piezas",
    "questionDetails": "Tengo dos grupos de piezas de metal similares.",
    "answer": "parts, pieces, pcs",
    "answerDetails": "I have two sets of similar metal parts."
  },
  {
    "id": 3581,
    "question": "camiseta",
    "questionDetails": "La camiseta del equipo es blanca y azul.",
    "answer": "shirt, jersey, tee",
    "answerDetails": "The team shirt is white and blue."
  },
  {
    "id": 3582,
    "question": "firmes",
    "questionDetails": "Si nos mantenemos firmes, no será el último.",
    "answer": "firm, steady, sign",
    "answerDetails": "If we hold firm, it won’t be the last."
  },
  {
    "id": 3583,
    "question": "harás",
    "answer": "stud"
  },
  {
    "id": 3584,
    "question": "daré",
    "answer": "Give"
  },
  {
    "id": 3585,
    "question": "guardo",
    "questionDetails": "Lo guardo en el agujero.",
    "answer": "keep",
    "answerDetails": "Keep it in the hole."
  },
  {
    "id": 3586,
    "question": "abiertos",
    "questionDetails": "Ojos y oídos abiertos.",
    "answer": "open",
    "answerDetails": "Eyes and ears open."
  },
  {
    "id": 3587,
    "question": "antecedentes",
    "questionDetails": "Antecedentes de la exposición, patrones de excavaciones arqueológicas.",
    "answer": "background",
    "answerDetails": "Background of the exhibit, patrons of archaeological digs."
  },
  {
    "id": 3588,
    "question": "cambiamos",
    "questionDetails": "Así que lo cambiamos.",
    "answer": "switched, change, swap",
    "answerDetails": "So we switched it out."
  },
  {
    "id": 3589,
    "question": "labios",
    "questionDetails": "Su voz, sus ojos sus manos, sus labios.",
    "answer": "lips",
    "answerDetails": "Your voice, your eyes your hands, your lips."
  },
  {
    "id": 3590,
    "question": "escapa",
    "questionDetails": "Nadie se me escapa.",
    "answer": "escapes, run away, flees",
    "answerDetails": "No one escapes me."
  },
  {
    "id": 3591,
    "question": "cargado",
    "questionDetails": "Programa cargado y listo.",
    "answer": "loaded",
    "answerDetails": "Program loaded and ready."
  },
  {
    "id": 3592,
    "question": "mercancía",
    "questionDetails": "Hay que asegurarse que la mercancía no se estropeé.",
    "answer": "goods, commodity, merchandise",
    "answerDetails": "We must ensure the goods don’t spoil."
  },
  {
    "id": 3593,
    "question": "gol",
    "questionDetails": "Pumas le ganó a Chivas con un marcador de 3 goles a uno.",
    "answer": "goal",
    "answerDetails": "Pumas beat Chivas by a score of three goals to one."
  },
  {
    "id": 3594,
    "question": "fiscal",
    "questionDetails": "El Congreso quiere reformar el sistema fiscal.",
    "answer": "tax, prosecutor",
    "answerDetails": "Congress wants to reform the tax system."
  },
  {
    "id": 3595,
    "question": "bronca",
    "questionDetails": "… algún otro lugar tienes dolor y bronca.",
    "answer": "anger",
    "answerDetails": "… somewhere you have pain and anger."
  },
  {
    "id": 3596,
    "question": "república",
    "questionDetails": "El resultado es una república.",
    "answer": "republic",
    "answerDetails": "The result to be a republic."
  },
  {
    "id": 3597,
    "question": "pobrecita",
    "questionDetails": "Pobrecita de mi madre.",
    "answer": "poor",
    "answerDetails": "Poor mother of mine."
  },
  {
    "id": 3598,
    "question": "canciones",
    "questionDetails": "Y ambos tienen canciones brillantes.",
    "answer": "songs, tunes, tracks",
    "answerDetails": "And you both have brilliant songs."
  },
  {
    "id": 3599,
    "question": "quietos",
    "questionDetails": "Los árboles están muy quietos.",
    "answer": "still, freeze",
    "answerDetails": "The trees are so still."
  },
  {
    "id": 3600,
    "question": "amas",
    "questionDetails": "Tienes que seguirlo, Teresa. Lo amas.",
    "answer": "you love him",
    "answerDetails": "You have to go after him, Teresa. You love him."
  }
]